

# KIM FULTON

# CONTENT AND COMMUNICATIONS LEAD

# PERSONAL PROFILE

I have ten years of professional experience as a writer and communicator, supported by several tertiary qualifications. I currently work as the Content and Communications Lead at Otago Polytechnic Auckland International Campus. I've previously worked as a journalist for daily newspapers throughout the country. I have bachelor's degrees in arts and science, a diploma in journalism, and a master's degree in creative writing.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

My news stories have appeared on the front pages of print editions of two of the country's biggest papers: The New Zealand Herald and the Dominion Post. I have also written for more than eight regional newspapers around the country. My fiction and poetry have appeared in Landfall, The New Zealand Poetry Society Anthology, Poetry NZ, JAAM, Hue and Cry, Mimicry, Takahe, Ngā Kupu Waikato: An Anthology of Waikato Poetry, The Pangolin Review, Stasis Journal, and Blackmail Press. I've recently published my first book of poetry.

## **AWARDS**

Value Ambassador Award

Otago Polytechnic Auckland International Campus | 2018

New Zealand Poetry Society International Poetry Competition
Second Place | 2018

Geometry Open Book National Poetry Competition

Judge's Selection | 2018

Takahe Monica Taylor Poetry Prize

Shortlisted | 2018

Cathay Pacific Travel Media Awards

Highly Commended AA New Travel Writer of the Year | 2010

Literary Artist of the Year for Palmerston North

Student City Arts Awards | 2008

## **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### Content and Communications Lead

Otago Polytechnic Auckland International Campus | Mar 2018-present

- Write student testimonials and graduate success stories
- Cover campus news and events
- Produce regular digital newsletters for staff, students and agents
- Manage the polytechnic's social media platforms
- Manage the campus's Covid-19 communications
- Keep the website up to date and ensure a steady flow of new content
- Develop content for print resources
- Take portrait and event photos.

## Journalist

NZME | May 2015-Dec 2016

- Pitched original stories based on information from sources, data and OIA requests
- Carried out interviews with people with a range of perspectives
- Produced stories on a range of topics including science, education, social issues,
   and health
- Wrote longform features on topics including immigration and religion in schools
- Loaded stories onto websites using CMS Zen.

#### **Journalist**

The Westport News | January 2012-March 2015

- Specialised as the court and emergency services reporter
- Also covered the environment, sport, mining, education, and council rounds
- Wrote up to five stories per day
- Filled in as chief reporter for periods of up to five weeks
- Subbed work, oversaw design and decided on story placement
- Wrote and voiced radio news bulletins for Coast FM.

#### **INTERESTS**

Outside of work, I love sport. I played cricket at a representative level and captained my school's first eleven team growing up. I now play for the women's premier reserve team at Suburbs New Lynn Cricket Club and help out with jobs around the club. I play soccer socially for the West Auckland Association Football Club, where I've been a member for more than 20 years.

#### **CONTACT DETAILS**

2/6 Craigbank Avenue,

New Lynn, Auckland

Phone: 021 253 4591

Email: kimjfulton87@gmail.com

## **REFERENCES**

# Deepika Kumar

Digital Marketing and Communication Manager Otago Polytechnic Auckland International Campus 021 861 844 deepika.kumar@op.ac.nz

#### Lee Scanlon

Chief Reporter
The Westport News
027 283 2408
lee@westportnews.co.nz

## **EDUCATION**

# Master of Creative Writing | 2017 - 2018

Massey University

My thesis consisted of a creative component and a research component. This degree was awarded with distinction.

# National Diploma in Journalism | 2011

Waikato Institute of Technology

This diploma covered news writing, news gathering, ethics, law, and shorthand. It included an internship at the Western Leader in Auckland and another at The Tribune in Palmerston North.

## Bachelor of Arts and Sciences | 2006 - 2009

Massey University

I completed this conjoint degree with majors in English and ecology.

# Digital Photography Training Certificate | 2018

Nelson Marlborough Institute of Technology

This 20-week course taught the fundamentals of documentary, portrait, and landscape photography.

## Certificate in Bicultural Competency | In progress

Otago Polytechnic

This course covers te reo, tikanga Māori, and the Treaty of Waitangi.